The JSDF was deployed to the Special Region.
特地に派遣された自衛隊　そこで第三偵察隊隊長の伊丹は
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
There, Itami, Captain of Recon
Squad 3, met the elf Tuka,
エルフテュカ　死神ロゥリィ　魔導士レレイと出会った
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 www.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
Rory the Reaper, and the mage Lelei.
日听 Keishin Cc  翻译 domi Akashi  校对 はばやし  小伍  时间轴 神埼魯蒙  压制 咸鱼
After the Empire suffered a massive defeat,
its third princess, Piña Co Lada,
そして大敗を期した帝国の第三皇女であるピニャ・コ・ラーダは
decided to go to Japan and negotiate.
交渉のため　日本へ赴く決意を固めた
In her diary, she wrote that when she crossed
彼女の日記にはこう記されている
the gate that marked the border between worlds,
世界の境たる「門」を潜り抜けると
she saw buildings which touched the sky.
そこは　摩天楼だった
Are those... walls?
これは壁…か
Look! There are people inside!
見ろ　中に人の姿がある
They're making effective use of limited space.
限られた土地を有効に活用している
Does that mean Itami's country is very tiny?
イタミの国はそれだけ狭いってことぉ？
Or perhaps that it's very populated.
もしくは人口がとても多いのかも
Either way,
いずれにせよ　これだけの建造物を作り上げる国家を相手に
the Empire has started a war against a civilization
capable of building these structures...
帝国は戦争を始めてしまったのだな
Thus, the JSDF Fought There!
to
kk
Thus, the JSDF Fought There!
u
ni
Thus, the JSDF Fought There!
na
特に何も望むことなんてない　身の程は知っているさ
Thus, the JSDF Fought There!
to
ni
I don't really have anything I'm wishing for
mo
no
kk
zo
to
u
mu
kk
ko
ni
to
u
na
n
te
na
i
ni
na
mo
ni
no
mo
zo
no
mu
zo
ko
mu
to
ko
na
to
n
na
te
n
na
te
i
na
mi
no
ho
do
wa
mi
i
sh
I pretty much know my place.
i
t
te
i
no
ru
mi
sa
ho
no
do
ho
wa
do
sh
wa
i
sh
t
i
te
t
i
te
ru
i
sa
ru
so
n
na
bo
ku
そんな僕でさえも奥の方に
so
sa
de
Even so, I think deep down that I don't wanna let anything go
sa
e
om
n
ou
so
o
ku
no
na
ho
n
u
ni
bo
na
ku
bo
de
ku
sa
de
e
sa
om
e
ou
om
o
ou
ku
o
no
ku
ho
no
u
ho
ni
u
yu
zu
ri
ta
ni
It seems I'm only playing "the good girl".
ku
譲りたくない　意向程度はあるらしい
yu
na
i
ii
ko
tte
zu
i
yu
to
ha
a
ru
ra
sh
i
ri
zu
ta
ri
ku
ta
na
ku
i
na
ii
i
ko
ii
tte
ko
i
tte
to
i
ha
to
a
ha
ru
a
ra
ru
sh
ra
i
sh
ma
mo
ru
t
i
Protecting something is harder than I thought,
te
ma
an
ga
守るって案外と難しいね
i
to
mu
mo
zu
ma
ka
sh
i
ru
ne
mo
t
ru
te
t
an
te
ga
an
i
ga
to
i
mu
to
zu
mu
ka
zu
sh
ka
i
sh
ne
i
a
ki
ra
ne
But it's not like that means I'm gonna give up!
me
ru
a
wa
ke
諦めるわけじゃないけど
ja
na
i
ke
ki
do
a
ra
ki
me
ra
ru
me
wa
ru
ke
wa
ja
ke
na
ja
i
na
ke
i
do
ke
ao
i
so
ra
no
ao
ha
At the far reaches of the blue sky - the end of these connected roads,
te
t
su
青い空の果て　繋がった道の行方
na
ga
t
i
ta
ao
mi
chi
no
yu
ku
e
so
i
ra
so
no
ra
ha
no
te
ha
t
te
su
t
na
su
ga
na
t
ga
ta
t
mi
ta
chi
mi
no
chi
yu
no
ku
yu
e
ku
hi
to
wa
e
People still won't come to understand one another... but I'm fine with that
wa
ka
ri
人と人は分かり合えない　だけどいいんじゃない？
a
to
e
hi
na
i
da
ke
do
ii
n
to
ja
na
i
hi
to
wa
ka
ri
a
e
na
i
da
ke
do
ii
n
ja
na
The door I'll open will have everything changing,
i
na
hi
ra
i
ta
to
hi
bi
i
ra
開いた扉は全てを変えてゆく
hi
wa
su
be
te
i
o
ra
ka
e
ta
te
i
yu
ku
to
ta
bi
to
ra
bi
wa
ra
su
wa
be
su
te
be
o
te
ka
o
e
ka
te
e
yu
te
ku
yu
so
re
wa
a
ka
so
ku
t
Just like the break of dawn!
それは暁のように
su
re
ki
so
no
yo
u
ni
wa
re
a
wa
ka
a
t
ka
su
t
ki
su
no
ki
yo
no
u
yo
ni
u
本当に寒いのね
It really is cold.
Episode 8  Japan, Beyond the Gate
I told you!
だから言ったでしょ
You okay? I can go get you a coat.
大丈夫か　コート借りて来るけど
No. I'm fine.
ううん　平気よ　このくらい
If you really think you need one, tell us.
本当に必要な時は言ってね
Okay.
Lieutenant Itami.
伊丹二尉
I am Komakado, from Intel HQ.
情報本部から参りました　駒門です
I've been instructed to escort you.
皆さんのエスコートを仰せつかっております
You with Public Safety?
おたく　公安の人？
You can tell?
分かりますか　さすがは英雄だ
That's a hero's sixth sense for you.
It was just a random guess.
たまたまだよ
A random guess, huh?
たまたまねえ
I looked into you.
調べたよ
You had the second-lowest grades in your class during officer training,
一般幹部候補生課程の成績は同期に怪我人が出たおかげでブービー
and only avoided last place because another trainee got injured.
After graduation and assignment, you rated "just barely passing."
任官後の評価は不可にならない程度に可
Your CO got pissed off and threw you into Ranger Officer School,
業を煮やした上官に幹部レンジャーに放り込まれ　なんとか終了
which you finished, somehow.
JSDF Narashino
Garrison
For some reason, you were transferred to Narashino after that.
その後　なぜか習志野に異動
Poor personal evaluations kept you at Second Lieutenant,
そこに難有りとして三尉に止めを置かれていたが
JSDF Narashino
Garrison
but after the incident in Ginza,
you were promoted to First Lieutenant,
例の事件のおかげで二尉に昇任した　と
I'm told.
You sure did your homework.
よく調べてるな
Slacker. Otaku.
「月給泥棒」　「オタク」　隊内ではコテンパンだねえ
Your reputation on post is horrible.
So how the hell did you end up an S?
そんなあんたがなんでSなんぞに
A special forces group modeled after
the US Army's Green Berets and Delta Force
You really did your homework.
ほんとよく調べてるよ
Did you know?
知ってるか
If a colony of ants gets rid of the laziest one,
蟻ってのは怠けてる個体を取り除くと　新たに怠ける奴が現れるそうだ
another one will just start being lazy instead?
So lazy people are necessary?
怠け者が必要だと？
さあね
I don't know.
But when my CO was yelling at me, I told him about that, and...
ただ　上官に叱られたときにこの話をしたら
You were transferred to the Special Forces Group.
特殊作戦群に転属になった
I was just trying to argue for the hell of it, though.
ただの屁理屈だったんだけど
Well, if people like you are taking it easy,
まあ　あんたみたいなのがのんびりやってれば　それはそれでよく回るのかもな
that might mean everything works better.
It can't be! Tell me it's not true!
うそよ　うそだと言って
Somebody like him's a Ranger and Special Forces?
こんな人がレンジャーな上に特戦だ
Well, excuse me.
悪かったな
You really are something special.
やっぱりあんたはタダ者じゃない
I've got a lot of respect for someone who can play the slacker
働き蟻の中で怠け者を演じられる神経を　俺は尊敬するよ
among a bunch of worker ants.
It's a lie! A lie! This is a dream!
うそよ　うそ　これは夢
I'm dreaming! This is impossible!
夢ったら夢よ　ありえない　ありえない
Get going.
出してくれ
Look at all the people.
すごい人
Is this a market?
ここは市場なのかしらぁ
A festival?
お祭り？
Look. What's that?
見て　何かしら
They've decorated a tree?
木に装飾が施されている
Maybe a charm of some sort?
何かのおまじないかしらぁ
Where are we going?
どこへ向かっているんですか？
We can't take them to the Diet Building wearing jeans, can we?
国会行くのに　ジーンズってわけにはいかないだろう
I guess when you've got a nice body, you look good in anything, including suits.
スタイルがいいとスーツも似合うわね
What will you two wear?
ロゥリィとレレイはどうする？
I'm fine.
不要
Me, too.
私も
This is formal wear for a priest.
これ　神官の正装だものぉ
Yeah, bill it to the JSDF...
領収証　陸上自衛隊で
Ushinoya
Here you go.
はい　お待ち
Why gyuudon?
なんで牛丼なんですか？
I have to expense our spending on the Diet trip,
参考人招致の間は出張費扱いで　一食五百円までしか出ないんだよ
and we only get 500 yen per meal.
Times are tough.
世知辛いっすね
What is this? Do we eat it raw?
これは　生のまま食べるのか
Your Highness!
殿下
You eat, too.
お前も食べておけ
If you're hungry, you won't have strength when you need it.
空腹では　いざという時に力を発揮できんぞ
Right.
はい
This is the Japanese Senate?
これがニホンの元老院…
Aren't we getting off?
妾たちも降りるのでは？
We'll be going to a different area.
自分たちは別の会場に向かいます
Officially, you aren't in Japan.
公式には　殿下は日本に来ていないことになっておりますので
I am Shirayuri Reiko, adviser to the Prime Minister.
首相補佐官の白百合玲子と申します
This is Sugawara Kouji-kun, with the foreign ministry.
こちらは外務省の菅原浩治君
This is not a peace conference.
これは講和会議ではありません
To ensure that we are on the same page in the event of such a conference,
その前段　交渉に関する様々な取り決めを話し合う場と認識して頂きたいのですが
we wish to discuss and decide on a number of matters here beforehand.
問題ありませんか？
Is that all right?
I have no objections.
異存ありません
It's been four months since the Ginza incident.
銀座事件から四ヶ月
The first question and answer session
本日国会において　初めての質疑応答が行われます
regarding this matter will be held in the diet today.
In addition to JSDF personnel who've been on the ground,
参考人として　現場の自衛隊員の他
保護された特地の住人が招かれています
refugees from the Special Region have been invited, as well.
They've just entered the building!
ただいま参考人が入ってきました
We will now ask questions of the witnesses.
これより　参考人に対する質疑に入ります
Special Region Refugees Taken in By the JSDF
Civilian Victims
Coda Village Evacuation
Refugee Camp Size
Special Region Refugees Taken in By the JSDF
Civilian Victims
Coda Village Evacuation
Refugee Camp Size
Special Region Refugees Taken in By the JSDF
Civilian Victims
Coda Village Evacuation
Refugee Camp Size
Special Region Refugees Taken in By the JSDF
Civilian Victims
Coda Village Evacuation
Refugee Camp Size
Special Region Refugees Taken in By the JSDF
Civilian Victims
Coda Village Evacuation
Refugee Camp Size
Special Region Refugees Taken in By the JSDF
Civilian Victims
Coda Village Evacuation
Refugee Camp Size
Special Region Refugees Taken in By the JSDF
Civilian Victims
Coda Village Evacuation
Refugee Camp Size
Special Region Refugees Taken in By the JSDF
Civilian Victims
Coda Village Evacuation
Refugee Camp Size
Special Region Refugees Taken in By the JSDF
Civilian Victims
Coda Village Evacuation
Refugee Camp Size
Special Region Refugees Taken in By the JSDF
Civilian Victims
Coda Village Evacuation
Refugee Camp Size
Special Region Refugees Taken in By the JSDF
Civilian Victims
Coda Village Evacuation
Refugee Camp Size
Special Region Refugees Taken in By the JSDF
Civilian Victims
Coda Village Evacuation
Refugee Camp Size
Special Region Refugees Taken in By the JSDF
Civilian Victims
Coda Village Evacuation
Refugee Camp Size
Special Region Refugees Taken in By the JSDF
Civilian Victims
Coda Village Evacuation
Refugee Camp Size
Special Region Refugees Taken in By the JSDF
Civilian Victims
Coda Village Evacuation
Refugee Camp Size
Diet Member                  Kouhara Mizuki
Special Region Refugees Taken in By the JSDF
Civilian Victims
Coda Village Evacuation
Refugee Camp Size
Special Region Refugees Taken in By the JSDF
Civilian Victims
Coda Village Evacuation
Refugee Camp Size
Special Region Refugees Taken in By the JSDF
Civilian Victims
Coda Village Evacuation
Refugee Camp Size
Special Region Refugees Taken in By the JSDF
Civilian Victims
I'll get straight to the point.
単刀直入にお尋ねします
Why were 150 special region refugees,
特地甲種害獣　通称ドラゴンによって
who were supposed to be under JSDF protection,
自衛隊保護下にあった現地の避難民150名が犠牲となったのはなぜでしょうか
killed by a Class-A Dangerous Animal you refer to as a "dragon"?
Witness Itami.
伊丹参考人
Uh, well...
えー　それは　ドラゴンが強かったからじゃないですかねぇ
Probably because the dragon was so strong.
How can you be so calm?
何を人ごとのように
Don't you feel any responsibility for the loss of those lives?
尊い命が失われたことに責任は感じないのですか？
I'm sad that so many were killed.
大勢の方が亡くなったのは残念に思います
I also felt that our own capabilities were lacking.
あと　力不足を感じましたね
So you're admitting the JSDF is at fault!
それは　自衛隊の非を認めるということですね
No. We lacked sufficient firepower.
いえ　不足していたのは銃の威力です
Our 7.62mm rounds bounced off it like they were BBs.
7.62mmなんてまるで豆鉄砲でした
I really wished we'd had a stronger weapon.
もっと強力な武器があればと　心底思いましたね
A charged particle beam, a railgun, a graviton bomb, or something.
荷電粒子砲とか　レールガンとか　重力子爆弾とか
If I may, chairman.
委員長
Our analysis of a sample from the Special Region shows that
特地から持ち帰ったサンプルを解析した結果
this "dragon" had scales as strong as tungsten,
通称ドラゴンはタングステン並の強度を持つ鱗に覆われ　超高温の火炎を吐く
and could exhale high-temperature flames.
いわば　空飛ぶ戦車であることが判明しております
It was, essentially, a flying tank.
Demanding zero casualties when fighting such a monster
そのような生物を相手に　犠牲者をゼロにしろというのは
is rather unreasonable, wouldn't you say?
いささか酷な話ではないでしょうか
Very well...
いいでしょう
Then my next question is for Lelei la Lalena.
では　レレイ・ラ・レレーナ参考人にお尋ねします
Do you understand Japanese?
日本語は分かりますか？
はい　すこし
Yes. A small amount.
She's so young.
幼いな
魔法使い？
A mage?
結構です
Very well.
I'm told you're living in a refugee camp right now.
今は難民キャンブで生活しているそうですが　不自由はありませんか？
Are there inconveniences there?
I do not understand what you mean by "inconveniences."
不自由の定義が理解不能
If you mean that not everything is convenient,
自由でないという意味なら　人は生まれながらにして自由ではないはず
then that's true for everyone.
I'll change the question, then.
言い方を変えましょう
Do you lack anything that you require?
生活する上で不足しているものはありませんか？
All of my clothing, food, shelter, work, and spiritual needs are being met.
衣・食・住・食・霊のすべてにおいて　必要は満たされている
If I started asking for more, there'd be no end to it.
質を求めるとキリがない
Then you do feel the JSDF's response in any way
では　150名もの死者が出た原因として
自衛隊の対応に問題はありませんでしたか？
contributed to the result of 150 casualties?
No.
ない
私はエルフ　ロドの森部族
I am an Elf of the Lodo Forest clan.
I am the daughter of Hodolue Ray,
ホドリュー・レイの娘　テュカ・ルナ・マルソー
Tuka Luna Marceau.
An elf?
エルフ？
Really?
本物か
失礼を承知でお尋ねしますが　その耳は本物ですか？
I know this is a rude question,
but are those ears real?
Yes, they are.
ええ　自前ですよ
触ってみますか？
Would you like to touch them?
Order! Order!
静粛に　静粛に
Th-Then, Tuka-san, was there any problem
で…では　テュカさん
ドラゴンに襲われた時　自衛隊の対応に問題はありませんでしたか？
with the way the JSDF handled the dragon attack?
I don't know...
よく分からない
I was unconscious at the time.
その時　気を失っていたから
Thank you.
結構です　では　次は…
Okay, next...
Witness Rory Mercury.
ロゥリィ・マーキュリー参考人
Black clothes and a veil.
黒服にベール
Those must be mourning clothes. That's perfect.
きっと喪服ね　都合がいいわ
What is your name?
お名前は
Rory Mercury.
ロゥリィ・マーキュリー
Describe your life in the refugee camp.
難民キャンプではどのような生活をしていますか？
It's very simple.
単純よ
When I wake up, I live. I pray.
朝　目を覚ましたら生きる　祈る
そして命を頂く　祈る
I receive life. I pray.
夜になったら眠る
Then at night, I sleep.
"Receive life"?
命を頂く？
Yes. I eat. I kill.
そう　食べること　殺すこと　エムロイへの供犠
I make offerings to Emloy...
A lot of different things.
色々よ
I'll reword the question.
質問を変えましょう
From the look of things, you've lost someone who matters a lot to you.
見たところ　あなたは大切な人を失ったようですが
Do you feel the JSDF is responsible?
そうなった原因が自衛隊にあるとは思いませんか？
She says she doesn't understand the question.
質問の意味がよく分からないと言っている　ロゥリィの家族…
Rory's family—
According to reports,
資料によれば　ドラゴンの襲撃を受けた際
despite the fact that one-fourth of the refugees were killed in the dragon attack,
避難民の四分の一を犠牲にしておきながら
the JSDF suffered no fatalities and not even a single injury!
自衛隊員には死者どころか　重傷を負った者すらいません
The people who should've defended you with their lives put their own safety first,
身を挺して戦うべきだった人間が自身の安全を第一に考え　結果
and in the end, put civilians in danger, right?
民間人を危険にさらしたのではありませんか？
さあ　話してください
Now, tell us!
What did you really see?
あなたが見た自衛隊の本当の姿を
Expose the JSDF's true colors!
あなたおバカぁ？
Are you stupid?
Wh-What did you just say—
い…今　なんと
I asked if you were stupid,
あなたはおバカさんですかぁ　と尋ねたのよぉ
お嬢ちゃん
little girl.
Thus, the JSDF Fought There!
You speak Japanese?
あなた　日本語が…
That doesn't matter.
そんなことはどうでもいいわよ
You want to know how they fought the dragon, right?
イタミたちがドラゴンとどう戦ったのか　それが知りたいのでしょう？
They did their absolute best.
イタミたちは頑張ってたわぁ
They most certainly did not use the refugees as shields
難民を盾にして安全な場所にいたなんてことは
and fight from a safe distance.
絶対にないわよぉ
But to begin with,
第一　兵士が自分の命を大切にして何が悪いの？
what's wrong with soldiers making sure they stay alive?
If they die needlessly,
彼らが無駄死にしたら
who's going to protect people like you,
あなたたちのように雨露凌げる場所で駄弁ってるだけの人を
who do nothing but sit in comfort and complain, little girl?
一体誰が守ってくれるのかしらぁ　お嬢ちゃん
Little... girl?
お嬢…ちゃん？
They fought a Fire Dragon and came back alive.
炎龍を相手にして生きて帰ってきた
The first thing you should do is praise them.
まずはそのことを褒めるべきでしょうに
Also,
それと　避難民の四分の一が亡くなったと言ったけど　それは違う
you said that one-fourth of the refugees died.
That's incorrect.
Itami's squad saved three-fourths of them.
イタミたちは四分の三を救ったのよ
If you can't even understand that,
そんなことも理解できないなんて　この国の兵士も苦労するわねぇ
the soldiers of this country must have a very hard time.
They succeeded in doing something no one else could do.
イタミたちは誰にもできないことをやり遂げたわ
That is my answer to your stupid question.
それがあたなのおバカな質問に対する答えよ
Do you understand, little girl?
お分かりかしらぁ？　お嬢ちゃん
You don't seem to know how to speak to your elders,
大人に対する礼儀がなってないようねぇ　お嬢ちゃん
"little girl"?
Are you referring to me?
それって私のことぉ？
Who else could there be?
他に誰がいますか
I don't know how it works in the Special Region,
特地ではどうか知りませんが　この国では年長者は敬うものですよ
but in this country we respect our elders!
I'm shocked...
驚いたわね　たかが…
How dare a mere...
Mr. Chairman!
委員長
Diet Member Kouhara is badly mistaken.
幸原議員は重大な勘違いをしておられます
なんで邪魔するのよぉ
Why are you getting in my way?
いいから　大人しくしててくれ
Just stay put!
Um...
えー　信じられないでしょうが
You may not believe this,
このロゥリィ・マーキュリーさんはこの場にいる誰よりも年長なのです
but Rory Mercury-san is the oldest person here.
Just how old is she?
一体いくつだというのです？
Nine-hundred and sixty-one years old.
九百六十一歳になるわ
N-Nine hundre—
きゅ…九百？
A-And how old is Tuka-san?
ち　ちなみに隣のテュカさんは…
I'm one-hundred and sixty-five.
百六十五歳よ
Don't tell me...
まさか…
No, I'm 15.
十五歳
I am human.
私はヒト種　その寿命は六十から七十年
Our race lives between 60 and 70 years.
Almost all of the residents of our world are human.
私たちの世界の住民はほとんどがこれ
Tuka is an elf. They do not age and live long.
テュカは不老長命のエルフ
中でも稀少な妖精種で　寿命は永遠に近いと言われる
She is a rare fairy type, who live almost eternally.
Rory was originally human, but when she became a demigod,
ロゥリィは元々ヒトだけど
亜神となった時　肉体年齢は固定された
her body stopped aging.
After a thousand years or so, her kind abandons physical existence,
通常は一千年ほどで肉体を捨て　霊体の使徒に
becoming first spirits, then gods.
やがては神になる
Thus, the concept of a "lifespan" does not apply to her.
従って　寿命という概念はない
A God has descended!!
Diet Broadcast
Hell yes---!!
Diet Member Kouhara, does this conclude your questions?
幸原議員　質問は以上ですか？
以上です
Yes.
Lastly, regarding the treatment of prisoners...
では　最後に捕虜の扱いですが
We currently hold, as prisoners,
around 6,000 of your soldiers.
現在我が国が囚えている貴国の将兵　その総数は約六千人です
Six thousand...?
六…千？
We would like to release them in response to your request.
我々はそちらの求めに応じる形で引き渡したいと思っております
How much ransom—
身代金はいかほどに？
Don't worry.
ご安心ください　我が国には捕虜を金銭で交換する慣習はございません
Our country does not engage in the custom of demanding ransom for prisoners.
We do expect to receive something in return, though.
ただ　「何らかの譲歩」は期待しております
Ginza Incident Prisoner List
Here's a list of the prisoners.
捕虜の名簿です
Ginza Incident Prisoner List
We can turn over a small number of them immediately.
このうち　若干名ならば　即時引き渡しが可能です
Many of the missing are children of Senators and nobles.
行方不明者の中には元老院議員や貴族の子弟も多くいます
If they're imprisoned...
もし捕虜となっていれば…
I know.
分かっている
He wants them released to grant favors for them back home.
彼らを解放し　向こうで恩を売ってこいとそう言っているのだ
That's what he's saying.
We'd like to examine the prisoner list before we answer.
その件については　名簿を精査した上で返答しましょう
Understood.
分かりました　本日の議題は以上です
That concludes our list of topics for the day.
Princess,
殿下
it's an honor to meet you.
お会いできて光栄でした
That's a greeting in our world.
こちらの挨拶です　手を握ってください
Clasp her hand.
I see.
そうか
Thank you for serving as our mediator for the negotiations.
交渉の仲介役　よろしくお願いします
I promise I'll do it.
約束しましょう
たった今　参考人招致を終えた特地住民の皆さんが出てきました
The Special Region's residents have completed their
session at the Diet and are leaving now!
They're leaving on a bus...
これからバスに乗って移動するようです
Command car to all cars.
指揮車より全車　お客さんがおいでなさったぞ
Our guests have arrived.
It opened.
開いた
So it did.
開いたね
Now's not the time for that. Get on quick!
って言ってる場合じゃない　早く乗って
急げ急げ
Hurry, Hurry!
Hurry!
早く
I look like I work at some kinda shady talent agency.
これじゃ怪しいタレント事務所のスタッフだな
Captain.
隊長
Hey, good work today.
ご苦労さん
I was panicking.
慌てましたよ
Nobody told me we were using the bus as a decoy.
バスを囮にするなんて話　聞いてなかったんで
Well, we met up, so it's okay, right?
ま　合流できたんだから　いいんじゃない
They've been shaking ever since the train went underground.
電車が地下に入ってから　ずっと怯えてるんです
They think we're taking them to the bottom of the Earth.
このまま地の底に連れていくつもりかーとか
They've never been on a subway. Can't blame 'em.
地下鉄も初体験だからな　無理ないか
My apologies.
失礼
It's fine...
いいえ
What's wrong?
どうした？　ロゥリィもダメか？
You too, Rory?
Hardy controls what's under the ground!
地面の下はハーディの領域なのよぉ
Hardy?
ハーディ？
She's bad news!
あいつヤバイのよぉ
Two hundred years ago she told me to marry her,
二百年前にもお嫁に来いってぇ　しつこくってしつこくってしつこくって
and she just wouldn't shut up about it!
She might drag me off to be her bride!
無理矢理お嫁さんにされかねないのぉ
So why are you clinging to me?
それで　なんで俺にしがみつく？
To keep her away!
ハーディ除けよぉ
Hardy doesn't like men,
あいつ男は嫌いだから　こうしてたら近寄ってこないかもしれないでしょう
so if I stay like this, maybe she won't come!
No, even it's a lie, this is what I want you to say.
いや　そこは嘘でもこう言ってくれ
"D-Don't get the wrong idea."
か…勘違いしないでよねぇ
"It's just to keep her away! It's just camouflage!"
ただの虫除け　カモフラージュなんだからぁ
Like that.
だろ
So creepy...
気持ち悪っ
Kasumigaseki. Kasumigaseki.
霞ヶ関駅　霞ヶ関駅
Hey there.
We're moving up the schedule and going to Hakone.
予定を早めて　箱根へ向かうぞ
We'll head to Tokyo and change trains there.
このまま東京まで行って乗り換えだ
How'd the bus work?
バスの方は？
They all fell for it.
見事に引っかかったよ
The fact that they didn't know about the change in plans
移動の手段の変更を知らなかった時点で
narrows the leak down to two suspects.
情報漏洩の容疑者は二人に絞り込めた
Right now I'm letting it go to find out where they're headed.
今　その行き先を突き止めるため泳がせている
イタミ
Itami!
ここから出たいの　もう　我慢できない
I want out!
I can't take it anymore!
We're almost done.
もう少しだ　次の次で降りるから
Two more stops.
ねぇ　早くぅ
Come on, hurry up!
Come on!
Next is Ginza. Ginza.
ねぇ　もう早くぅ
次は銀座　銀座です　乗り換えのご案内です
Hurry!
Transfer Information:
Please transfer here for Hibiya and Ginza lines.
日比谷線　銀座線はお乗り換えください
We'll be getting off here.
俺たち　ここで降りるよ
What?
なに？
You can't act on your own!
勝手に動かれちゃ困る　こっちにも段取りってもんが…
東京メトロをご利用の皆様にお知らせします
There's a plan for this—
The Marunouchi line is currently not functioning due to a
現在丸の内線は銀座－東京間で発生した架線事故の影響で運休しています
wiring accident between the Ginza and Tokyo stations.
There is presently no set time for it to be back online.
運転再開の目処は立っておりません
The Marunouchi line is currently not functioning—
現在丸の内線は銀座－東京間で発生し…
The air is filthy, but it's a million times better than underground.
まずい空気だけど　地下より一万倍ましだわぁ
They're shutting down the subway?
地下鉄まで止めるなんて　敵さん何が目的だと思う？
What do you think our enemy's goal is?
A demonstration.
デモンストレーションだな　いつでも手を出せると警告したいんだ
They want to warn us that they can hit us whenever they want.
But they failed with both the bus and the subway.
だが　バスと地下鉄　二度続けて失敗した
Subway Status
Maru-no-uchi Line
Operation Postponed
Location               Ginza-Tokyo Line
Cause                   Wiring Issue
Recovery ETA      Not Specified
Next, they'll do something more direct and obvious.
次はもっと直接的で分かりやすい行動に出てくるだろう
For example...
例えば…
Like that.
ほーら　こんなふうにな
What are you doing, moron?
何やってんだ　こいつは
Jeez.
ったく
Oh, that's...
それは…
What?
なんだ
What a wimp.
だらしないわね　このくらいで
It's not that heavy.
No normal person could lift that.
普通の人間には無理
For tonight, head to the Ichigaya Assembly Hall...
とりあえず　今晩は市ヶ谷会館に…
Shall we go there, then?
では　そこに向かいますか？
No, wait a second.
いや　ちょっと待って
We are not going to Akihabara.
秋葉原なら行きませんよ
That's not it...
そうじゃなくて…
携帯が止まった
My cellphone's shut off.
Fire at Ichigaya Assembly Hall.  Could it be Arson?
My gas has been shut off.
ガスも止まった
Fire at Ichigaya Assembly Hall.  Could it be Arson?
Immediate
Response Required
Not too much longer for the water...
Immediate
Response Required
水道もヤバイ
Immediate
Response Required
I'm hungry.
腹減った
あと１ページ　明日中に入稿しないと…
I need to turn in one more page by tomorrow...
At least turn on the heater.
エアコンくらいつけろよ　寒いぞこの部屋
This place is cold.
F-Food!
ご　ご飯
Right, right. I bought it for you.
はいはい　ちゃんと買ってきたよ
So warm...
あったかーい
Guys, come in for now.
皆　構わず入ってくれ
Um... Lieutenant?
あのう　二尉
Who is that?
誰です？　その人
Oh, this is...
これは…
My ex-wife.
俺の元嫁さんだ
Ex...
元？
...wife?
嫁…さん？
unmei niwa sakaraenai ne deatteshimatta
I guess I just can't fight my fate - we've already met!
運命には逆らえないね　出会ってしまった
何があるか分からないけれど　キミと出かけよう
nani ga aru ka wakaranai keredo
I don't know what might happen,
kimi to dekakeyou
but I'm heading out with you!
心おどる遠い景色は　なんだか違って
kokoro odoru tooi keshiki wa
There's something a bit different
nandaka chigatte
about the far off scenery,
doa o akete itsumo no choushi sa
But once we open the door, we're back to
ドアを開けて　いつもの調子さ　どうぞよろしく！
douzo yoroshiku
our usual pace, so let's keep on together!
mada kimerarenai sanpo koosu
We still can't decide which course to walk
まだ決められない散歩コース
いろんなものが多すぎて
iron na mono ga oosugite
There are just too many things to consider.
hikari no uzu ni suikomarete
Pulled into a whirlpool of light,
光のうずに吸い込まれて　まだ迷ってるの？
mada mayotteru no
We're still undecided!
走り抜けたあの瞬間は　甘い甘い香りの中で
hashirinuketa ano shunkan wa
Amidst a sweet, sweet scent,
amai amai kaori no naka de
We can feel a new future within this place.
arata na mirai koko ni kanjiteru
Upon a song, disappearing high into the sky,
新たな未来　ここに感じてる
tondekieru uta ni noseta
But the moment we manage to run on through
飛んで消える歌にのせた　空へ空へきれいな星に
sora e sora e kirei na hoshi ni
I'll cast a spell that sparkle brightly,
キラキラ光るように　魔法かけようから
kirakira hikaru you ni mahou kakeru kara
I'll cast magic which shines bright
Episode 9  The Hakone Mountain Night Battle
Next time on GATE:
"The Hakone Mountain Night Battle."
次回　「ゲート」
箱根山中夜戦